// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "Art is",
    answer: "creative expression",
    options: [
      "ability to paint",
      "ability to perform",
      "ability to carve creativity",
      "creative expression"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "Fine art comprises",
    answer: "",
    options: [
      "drawing, painting and carving",
      "drawing painting and culpture",
      "painting, textile and drawing",
      "texting, painting and ceramic"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "The rainbow colours are usually abbreviated as",
    answer: "ROYGBIV",
    options: [
      "ROYVIBG",
      "ROVGIBY",
      "ROYGBIB",
      "ROYGBIV"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "A gallery is a place where",
    answer: "works of arts are displayed for sale",
    options: [
      "works of arts are displayed for sale",
      "works of arts are garnished",
      "people converge for meeting",
      "artist works"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Basic shapes includes one of the following",
    answer: "circle",
    options: [
      "scroll",
      "zig-zag",
      "sprial",
      "circle"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Which of these colours is a complementary of green?",
    answer: "red",
    options: [
      "red",
      "yellow",
      "blue",
      "black"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "The components of Cultural and Creative Arts include the following EXCEPT",
    answer: "science",
    options: [
      "drama",
      "music",
      "science",
      "dance"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Colours placed side by side on the colour wheel are called",
    answer: "anaglogous colours",
    options: [
      "neutral colour",
      "warm colour",
      "anaglogous colours",
      "friendly colours"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Another name for beauty in art is",
    answer: "aesthetic",
    options: [
      "feeling",
      "beautification",
      "reality",
      "aesthetic"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Applied art includes the following designs EXCEPT",
    answer: "painting",
    options: [
      "ceramics design",
      "painting",
      "textile design",
      "graphic design"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "Which of these is not a type of line??",
    answer: "purchasing department",
    options: [
      "point",
      "spriral",
      "horizontal",
      "verticial"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 12,
    question: "Chiaroscuro in art means",
    answer: "light and shade",
    options: [
      "black and shade",
      "light and shade",
      "smooth and rough",
      "dark and cool"
    ]
  },


  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "The person that directs orchestra on choir in the church is called ",
    answer: "conductor",
    options: [
      "conductor",
      "director",
      "captain",
      "manager"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 14,
    question: "Which of the following colours is common to purple and green?",
    answer: "red",
    options: [
      "yellow",
      "red",
      "green",
      "blue"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 15,
    question: "Musical note consist if",
    answer: "7",
    options: [
      "9",
      "8",
      "7",
      "6"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 16,
    question: "Which of these materials is one colour?",
    answer: "charcoal",
    options: [
      "chalk",
      "crayon",
      "charcoal",
      "pastel"
    ]
  },


  {
    numb: 17,
    question: "An artiste means a",
    answer: "musician",
    options: [
      "musician",
      "graphic artist",
      "textile designer",
      "painter"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 18,
    question: "An imprrovised brush can be made from",
    answer: "quill feather",
    options: [
      "stick",
      "wood",
      "quill feather",
      "fish tail"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 19,
    question: "Which of these sets of colours are primary colour",
    answer: "red, yellow and blue",
    options: [
      "red, blue and black",
      "red, yellow and blue",
      "red, yellow and orange",
      "red, blue and green"
    ]
  },



  {
    numb: 20,
    question: "Texture refers to the",
    answer: "quality of the surface of an artwork",
    options: [
      "gradition of tones in a drawing",
      "quality of the surface of an artwork",
      "arrangement of froms in an artwork",
      "three dimensional illsioun in a drawing"
    ]
  },


  {
    numb: 21,
    question: "Which of these requires the use of fixative",
    answer: "chalk pastel",
    options: [
      "poster colour",
      "crayon",
      "oil painting",
      "chalk pastel"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 22,
    question: "One of the following is NOT an artist's tool",
    answer: "paint",
    options: [
      "palette",
      "brush",
      "chisel",
      "paint"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 23,
    question: "An abstract art art is reffered to as",
    answer: "non-figurative art",
    options: [
      "figurative art",
      "imaginative art",
      "non-figurative art",
      "natural art"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 24,
    question: "Which of the following does not belong to the group?",
    answer: "balance",
    options: [
      "shape",
      "line",
      "balance",
      "texture"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 25,
    question: "The arrangement of different shapes or froms in a reapting order is called",
    answer: "despatch office",
    options: [
      "ornametation",
      "pattern",
      "design",
      "decoration"
    ]
  },
];